Luke Broding

Gainesville, FL 32601 | (813) 417-4133 | lbroding@ufl.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/lukebroding

EDUCATION

University of Florida, Warrington College of Business *Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Marketing*

August 2021 - Present Gainesville, FL

• Certificate in A.I. Fundamentals and Applications

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven marketing professional with 3+ years of experience in social media management, market research, and marketing campaign strategy. Developed proficiencies in CRM and automation tools (HubSpot, eAgent) as well as technical skills related to data analytics, including Python and SQL. Skilled in devising creative strategies to achieve marketing objectives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fidelis Leadership Group

June 2020 - Present

Marketing Assistant and Social Media Coordinator

Tampa, FL (Remote)

- As a Marketing Assistant conducted market research, edited podcast episodes with audio engineering software, and performed social media archiving and organization to streamline the publication process for the organization.
- Promoted to Social Media Coordinator in February 2023 managed corporate social media accounts and coordinated content calendars for each platform to establish timely and relevant posts on Facebook, LinkedIn, and YouTube.
- Posted shareable content that resonated with followers, driving increased engagement rates by 10% and overall audience growth by 25%.
- Monitored comments sections across platforms to address feedback and maintain brand reputation.
- Produced and distributed podcast episodes on a weekly basis, enabling the organization to reach a broader audience.

ManpowerGroup

Marketing Intern

June 2024 - August 2024

Milwaukee, WI (Remote)

- Conducted extensive market research across multiple industries for Experis Game Solutions and Experis Health
 Solutions as well as created executive summaries and infographics for presentations based on B2B marketing.
- Created new product launch strategies for a nurse triage campaign for Experis Health Solutions and developed marketing campaign goals to improve KPIs, such as 20 prospective clients in the next quarter.
- Conducted competitor analysis and presented website improvements to key stakeholders for Experis Game Solutions, explaining my vision for a reorganization of services with a focus on user research and game development to better align with industry standards and enhance SEO.

Allstate Insurance Company

August 2023 - April 2024

Gainesville, FL

Sales and Marketing Intern

- Utilized CRM software to manage customer information, streamlining processes within the sales team.
- Implemented email and direct mail marketing campaigns that led to higher open rates and increased lead generation by 10% during Q4 of 2023.
- Conducted cold calling sessions and developed sales presentations that effectively communicated deep knowledge of product benefits to prospective clients.
- Assisted in the planning and execution of promotional events and marketing campaigns, resulting in increased brand awareness and long-term customer retention.

LEADERSHIP & INVOLVEMENT

Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity at the University of Florida (Alpha Eta Chapter)
Social Media Director and Photographer

August 2022 - August 2023

Gainesville, FL

- Coordinated marketing actions for new member recruitment, resulting in a 53% increase in new members compared to the previous fall semester.
- Created a content calendar and managed a post schedule throughout the fall and spring semesters.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete Python Bootcamp From Zero to Hero in Python Pierian Training
- HubSpot Digital Marketing Certification
- Apple Search Ads Certification

Luke Broding Page 2

SKILLS

- Marketing Campaign Strategy
- Market Research and Analysis
- Social Media Management
- AI and Machine Learning Fundamentals
- Programming and Data Analysis Python, SQL
- CRM Software HubSpot, eAgent
- Microsoft Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint, SharePoint, Outlook, Teams
- Adobe Creative Cloud Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Acrobat, InDesign, Lightroom
- Google Workspace Drive, Docs, Sheets, Slides
- Graphic Design and Media Production Software Canva, Ableton Live, Pixlr